Ryan Chen 陳俊綱

cell: 0966395847 • email: ryan26tw@yahoo.com

OBJECTIVE

To obtain a full-time position in Sr. Front-End Engineer.

PROFILE

A passionate and self-motivated Web Developer with 15+ years of professional experience in web development. A proactive learner and team player with experience in an agile and teamwork environment. Specialize in turning UI designs into clean, scalable and maintainable web sites and applications.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Gorilla Technology - Taipei City, Taiwan • Dec 2017 - Present

- Work on the front-end web applications development for the various company's products and projects.
- Discuss and design the technical specifications with the Product Manager to come up with the product UX flow to create great user experiences.
- Provide feedback and technical aspects with the Product Manager and UI team in the design meetings.
- Develop, maintain, test, build and deliver the high quality front-end code.

Front End Developer, ASUS - Taipei City, Taiwan • May 2017 - Nov 2017

- Responsible for building the ASUS ROG Forum site from scratch.
- Help identify and fix the bug for the company global official website.
- Develop and maintain the official websites and internal sites in the company.

Sr. Software Engineer, Verizon - San Jose, CA USA • August 2014 - May 2017

- Work closely with Product Managers and UI/UX Designers to clarify product specs and functional flows.
- Provide insights and feedbacks on technical aspects when the new project begins.
- Participate in brainstorm sessions to gather input to apply changes for prototype iterations.
- Build high quality and top performance applications that work on various browsers and devices.

Web Developer (Contractor), Google - Mountain View, CA USA • May 2013 - May 2014

- Develop and maintain innovative and informative websites for the worldwide Google users.
- Fulfill several project requests and bug fixes simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
- Responsible for the creation of high quality, world class web content for desktop and mobile devices.
- Work with Marketing and Product Managers to receive feedbacks and requests of the projects.

Staff Software Engineer, E*TRADE - Menlo Park • CA USA, October 2011 - April 2013

- Responsible for building the UI of the web-based mobile application for tablets.
- Work with Product Manager and QA for the development and testing cycle of the application.
- Develop pixel precision pages to support different mobile platforms and browsers.
- Responsible for debugging cross-browser and cross-platform issues on touch screen devices.

Web Developer, QuinStreet - Foster City, CA USA • August 2006 - August 2011

- Collaborate with Web Producers to innovate and create websites to meet the company's business goals.
- Develop and test the code to improve sites overall performance, effectiveness and usability.
- Implement components for new features to improve content relevance and SEO best practices.
- Responsible for both client-side and server-side development, as well as the MySQL database designs.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Proficient in front-end languages HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Solid knowledge of JavaScript frameworks in React, Vue.js, AngularJS.
- Strong knowledge of Material-UI, Bootstrap, DOM, Sass and Responsive Web Design.
- Working knowledge in Git version control, Source Tree, webpack, Postman and Chrome developer tool.
- Experience in Node.js, Express, Jenkins build and Jest JavaScript Testing Framework.
- Solid understanding of MySQL database and NoSQL database with MongoDB.
- Experience in programming with Python, PHP and Java. Familiar with linux commands.
- Understanding of HTTP, SEO, accessibility, cross-platform and cross-browser compatibility.

SKILLS

Software: Proficient in operating Mac OS and Microsoft Windows / Office. Language: Fluency in Chinese and English. Basic knowledge in Japanese.

Certificate: Japanese-Language Proficiency Test (JLPT) N4 certified, January 2010.

Personality: Excellent communication skills. Good interpersonal skills and strong attention to details.

PORTFOLIO

RyanChenWeb - http://www.ryanchenweb.com
LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryan-chen-web

EDUCATION

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA USA • B.S. in Electrical Engineering • December 2004